Curriculum Vitae

Elle Mouton

Date of Birth: 20/08/1997 Nationality: South African Phone: 071 118 6141

Email: elle.mouton@gmail.com

Home Address: 6 Leeuwendal Crescent, Gardens, 8001 Social Media Links: LinkedIn, Github, Instagram, Facebook



Personal Statement

I recently completed a BSc degree in Electrical and Computer engineering at the University of Cape Town and am now working at Luno (a cryptocurrency exchange) as a graduate backend software engineer.

I have taken special interest in the fascinating world of cryptography, Bitcoin and the Lightning Network. I started learning about the workings of Bitcoin and the Lightning Network at the start of 2019 and have since worked my way through the books *Mastering Bitcoin* and *Programming Bitcoin* and have also delved into the workings of the Lightning Network using online resources. I enjoyed the logical aspect of the cryptocurrency world so much that I decided to incorporate it into my final year project for my degree. My final year project at UCT was the development and analysis of an incentivised mesh-network using Bitcoin and the Lightning Network. I received 92% for this project.

Experience

January 2020 - present: I work as a graduate backend software engineer at Luno: a cryptocurrency

exchange based in Cape Town. At Luno, I am apart of the Cryptosec team which is a small team in charge of anything to do with sending receiving and storing cryptocurrencies. One of my biggest tasks at Luno so far has been to integrate bitcoin sends to Bech32 addresses (sends to native

segwit addresses).

December 2018: I completed a five week internship at Aerobotics as a data scientist intern.

During this time, I wrote a number of image and data processing

algorithms that have been put into production.

July 2018: I completed a two week bootcamp internship at MWR InfoSecurity where

learned how to do basic website penetration testing.

January 2016: I worked as the production secretary during the making of a film in the UK

where I was responsible for various administrative tasks.

2014 - 2019: I worked as a part time model for a total of 5 years. I spent four years at

The Circle Model management and one year at Twenty Model

Management.

Education

I recently completed a Bachelor of Science degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering at the University of Cape Town. I received first class honors for this degree and my overall GPA was 88%.

Fourth Year Research Project (Final Year Project) (92%)

Digital Systems (89%)

Digital Signal Processing (84%)

Introduction to C++ and Operating Systems (91%)

Engineering Design (79%) Law for Engineers (70%)

Professional Communication (75%)

New Venture Planning (75%) Industrial Ecology (79%)

Third Year Electromagnetic Engineering (100%)

Computer Science 2001 (Data structures and databases) (91%) Computer Science 2002 (Parallel and concurrent computing)(88%)

Control Systems Engineering (100%)

Design Principles (84%)

Electronic Devices and Circuits (89%)

Signals and Systems 2 (93%)

Electrical and Computer Engineering Design (89%)

Embedded Systems II (89%)

Second Year: Analogue Electronics (96%)

Embedded Systems 1 (89%)

Vector Calculus (94%)

Intro to Engineering Mechanics (95%)

Signals and Systems 1 (97%)

Linear Algebra and Differential Equations (94%)

Electromagnetism (84%)

Introduction to Power engineering (81%)

First Year: Mathematics 1 (82%)

Mathematics 2 (100%) Physical Sciences 1 (82%) Physical Sciences 2 (87%)

Intro to Electronic Engineering (82%) Intro to Electrical Engineering (90%) Computer Science 1 (Python) (90%) Computer Science 2 (Java) (85%)

Programming Languages

Java, Python, C++ and Go

Courses

2019: Completed the Go: The Complete Developer's Guide (Golang) on Udemy.

2018: Completed the Front End Development course offered by www.freecodecamp.org.

2017: Enrolled in the online machine learning course offered by Stanford University.

2016: Cape Peninsula University of Technology basic mechanical skills course (basics in hand skills, welding, robotics and pneumatics)

Academic Record

2019

Received certificate of excellence for first semester computer science course (CSC3023F)

2018:

- Awarded the Bain Merit award which goes to the highest achieving 3rd year engineering student across all disciplines.
- Awarded the overall 3rd year Class Medal for Electrical and Computer engineering
- Achieved an overall GPA of 88%
- Received certificate of excellence for first and second semester computer science courses (CSC2001S and CSC2002S)
- Received the Peralex Electronics Prize awarded to the best student in the Embedded Systems II course (EEE3094S)
- Deans Merit List

2017:

- Awarded the overall 2nd year Class Medal for Electrical and Computer engineering
- Received the Bain Merit Award prize (Awarded to the top two students in second year Engineering)
- Received the Bain Celebrating Women in Engineering award (Awarded to the top woman academic achiever in second year Engineering)
- · Achieved a GPA of 89%
- Deans Merit list

2016:

- Received a certificate of excellence for first year computer science.
- Achieved a GPA of 86% for my first year of study. This includes receiving 100% for first year mathematics.
- Took part in a team of four in the annual Standard Bank programming challenge.
- · Deans Merit List

2015:

Final matrix exam:

Certificate for being ranked 1st in Life Sciences (Biology) at RGHS Certificate for being ranked 1st in Geography at RGHS Achieved distinctions in all eight subjects

• Selected by RGHS to represent the school at the annual MINTEK physical sciences challenge.

2013-2015: Received full academic colours (over 80% aggregate for each year).

Skills

- Leadership skills:

I have developed great leadership skills through out my sporting activities as I have been named captain of three touch ruby teams that I have been apart of.

- Self-reliance:

I traveled to the UK for eight weeks by myself at the end of my final school year and in this time I have learnt about how to think and act for myself. I am also very good at working independently.

Communication:

While in the UK, I worked as the production secretary on the set of an independent film for five weeks. In this position, I was constantly required to interact with people in various lines of work and so I learned how to improve my communication skills. I speak both English and Afrikaans fluently.

During my time working as a model I also learned how to communicate effectively with people from all different types of backgrounds and nationalities.

- Time management:

Because of my studies, sporting and music commitments, I have developed very effective time management skills.

- Languages:

English and Afrikaans

Extra-curricular

I like to keep fit by rock-climbing, kitesurfing, mountain biking and skateboarding. I was captain of RGHS first touch rugby team and also represented Western Province at the National Championships from 2012-2016.

I received grade five level in Spanish guitar.

I also enjoy traveling and experiencing different cultures and ways of thinking. I lived in Seattle, USA with my family for four years and have traveled to the UK, Portugal, France and Australia.

References

Benji Meltzer:

CTO at Aerobotics where I was a data science intern for 5 weeks.

Email: benji@aerobotics.com